## Nwakaego Gift Eze

Cell: 613 252 4970 | Email: n.eze@hotmail.co.uk | Ottawa, ON, K4A 1E5

LinkedIn: <a href="https://bit.ly/NGiftEze">https://bit.ly/NGiftEze</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://bit.ly/3yObjzU">https://bit.ly/NGiftEze</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://bit.ly/3yObjzU">https://bit.ly/3yObjzU</a> | GitHub: <a href="https://bit.ly/2WUvyi7">https://bit.ly/2WUvyi7</a>

### SUMMARY

A highly motivated and productive Full stack web developer with a background in test automation using primarily selenium frameworks. Recently earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the Carleton University Bootcamp.

Bringing an extensive knowledge of JavaScript/jQuery, semantic HTML/CSS, React, modern JS libraries, Bootstrap, MySQL, and other similar systems, alongside a solid understanding of software development lifecycle as well and Agile methodologies. Possess a strong analytic and problem-solving skills with creative thinking and a keen desire to provide the best user experience as well as innovative applications for the clients while being part of a fast-paced, goal-oriented team.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: HTML/CSS, SQL, NoSQL, JavaScript, C#, Java
- Applications: GitHub, Heroku, MongoDB, MySQL, Microsoft Azure DevOps, Microsoft Test Manager
- Tools: Bootstrap, Express, ¡Query, Node, React, Handlebars

### **PROJECTS**

### Movie Mania | GitHub Movie Mania | View Movie Mania

- Summary: Movie database application that allows a registered user to search for and save movies as well as view details of the various movies.
- Role: Back-end developer
- Tools: React, GraphQL, Node, Express, MongoDB

## Workout Tracker App | GitHub Workout Tracker | View Workout Tracker

- Summary: An application built with the focus on the back end to track user workouts; the user can create, view, and track their daily workouts
- Role: Sole Author
- Tools: ExpressJS, MongoDB, Mongoose

## Weather Dashboard | GitHub Weather Dashboard | View Weather Dashboard App

- Summary: A web application that enables the user to view the weather both current and forecast, of different cities. The user search history is saved and displayed for easy reach and can be referred to at any time
- Role: Sole Author
- Tools: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap framework, Server side APIs, Moment JS

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Accenture December 2019 – Present Business and Integration Technology Senior Analyst Ottawa, ON

- Took on the role of the Subject Matter Expert (SME) and point of contact for all teams with regards to insurance applications (one of the major revenue-generating legacy systems for the government of Canada client) and in the process earned recognitions from the client and account leadership on successful delivery of high priority urgent projects delivered in great quality
- Led all test efforts on all insurance-related projects and systems (one of the major revenue-generating legacy systems) for the government of Canada client effectively and efficiently and delivered quality products within the given timelines.

- Led the support effort for the user acceptance test (UAT) with the client and constantly worked to resolve all issues that may arise during these tests with the client, developers and all parties involved at this phase while keeping everyone on track especially when dealing with tight deadlines.
- Constantly implemented, troubleshooted and educated all stakeholders involved on the use of the Azure DevOps tool to ensure a streamlined process resulting in effective management as well as high quality deliverables
- Performed system test for various applications such as CRM (Dynamics 365), ERP, web applications and Mainframe applications to deliver quality product
- Effectively utilised the Azure DevOps tool to produce daily reports and metrics to inform test manager of progress made and consequently keep documentation of process for projects for possible future reference
- Ensure all stakeholders are aligned to the business requirement for each project to avoid scope creep
  and the clients pushing in requirements that were not accounted for into production, which could result
  in system failure or defect in production.
- Maintain and runs automated test scripts using selenium Frameworks and continuous improvement in the quality of the product to meet client needs and handle design reviews
- Constantly provide knowledge transfer sessions to team members where necessary on insurance projects as well as assisting in onboarding of newly welcomed team members
- Independently worked on several projects, (more than 35 projects) for a combination of the insurance applications, CRM and finance applications from start to finish

## Accenture March 2017 – Dec 2019 Business and Integration Architect Technology Analyst Ottawa, ON

- Applied the knowledge of software development cycle methodology and communicating effectively with business clients and development team
- Liaised with the client and the development team to design and create the test plan and test data required for the testing efforts while understanding the client requirement while mastering the different applications at the given time
- Performed Front-end testing of website and mainframe applications for different projects and teams for various Government of Canada clients using Team Foundation Server and HP Quality center
- Led the testing efforts for a critical client application for the assisted housing projects that involved working with web-based application (as the front end for the end user) as well as the Mainframe application (as the back end for the client)
- Acted as the interim team lead for the onshore operations test team with responsibilities such as allocating resources to various projects as they come in, estimating timelines during project life cycle and monitoring project reports from team to pass on to the leadership for project tracking
- Liaised with offshore resources to perform analytics testing of cloud-based application CRM(D365) to
  ensure that the specific data needed by the client for their customized data analysis worked as
  expected
- Worked on over 30 different client-facing projects from start to finish independently and ensured client satisfaction for each of these projects
- Carried out successful knowledge transfers for new team members on various applications to ensure a good understanding of these applications and how they work

## ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

## David's Bridal Ottawa Associate (Part-time)

July 2015 – February 2017 Ottawa, ON

- Provided excellent customer relations and support by listening to customers' needs and educate them on the various choices available as well as resolving their issues.
- Maximized sales and customer satisfaction by providing superior service and ensuring that their needs are met.
- Demonstrated good organization and time management skills during appointments with clients.

## EF University Preparation, Cambridge, UK Work Placement as an Assistant to IT Manager

January – March (2012) Cambridge, Cambridgeshire

- Provided support and assistance with network upgrades, troubleshooting and technical resolution to staff as at when needed.
- Designed and implemented student surveys on course satisfaction for the institution.
- Performed Health Check on each Desktops and Laptops before the deployment process and ensured that all computers and IT equipment were always in good working condition.
- Created new users accounts for new user using the easy tech setup services.
- Maintained and monitored technical support issues for staff.
- Designed and maintained web-based applications built on various web technologies such as HTML, JavaScript.
- Made professional and effective inquiries by phone and email to different companies about various IT facilities needed for the smooth running of EF Institution to determine the best choice of equipment to meet the requirement of the school.
- Customized and evaluated the webpage of EF University Preparation, Cambridge during work placement to ensure ease of accessibility for students and other users.

### University of Sunderland, UK Student Representative for MSC Computing

Sep 2012 - December 2013 Sunderland, Tyne & Wear

- Reported student queries and concerns to appropriate division/department or the faculty board, as appropriate
- Participated and represented classmates in various academic board meetings and student forum meetings
- Disseminated information and feedback about relevant discussions at the various faculty board meetings to fellow students
- Negotiated in meetings with heads of departments on students' requests in order to effectively ensure students' input are considered for effective running of the school.

### **EDUCATION/QUALIFICATION**

2021, Certificate (Full Stack Web Developer Boot Camp) Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

2016, MEng (Engineering Management) University of Ottawa, ON

2013, MSc. (Computing) University of Sunderland, Tyne & Wear

2012, **Pre-masters Diploma (Information Technology)** EF University Preparation, Cambridge, Cambridgeshire

2009, **BSc.** (Human Anatomy) University of Port-Harcourt, Nigeria.

### PRESENTATION:

Thesis Title: The Deployment of Cryptographic Approaches (E.G. RPKI) in Securing BGP Routes. December 2013.

### TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900) 2016

2020